Guide to the Beau Geste Press Ephemera, 1970-1976
Department of Special Collections
Beau Geste Press Ephemera,
1970-1976
Special Collections M0702
Beau Geste Press.
2.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1994.
History
The Beau Geste Press existed in England between 1971-1974. It was founded by Felipe Ehrenberg, David Mayor, Chris Welch, and Martha Hellion. It printed the works of visual poets, conceptualists, and neo-dadaists, many of whom were closely tied to the Fluxus movement. The press printed artist books using inexpensive materials, such as mimeograph machines, cheap paper, and staples. Consequently, many of the materials in the collection are rather fragile. In 1974 the Beau Geste Press merged with several similar presses to form BAAA, the Beau and Aloes Arc Association.
Scope and Content
Editions of the press' serial publication, "Schmuck," contain works of several artists from a single country, such as Iceland, France, and Hungary.
Access Terms
Ehrenberg, Felipe.; Hellion, Martha.; Mayor, David.; Welch, Chris.; Beau and Aloes Arc Association (BAAA); Arts, Modern--20th century.; Dadaism.; Printing--Great Britain.; Visual poetry.; Schmuck.
Container List
- Accession 1994-094
  - Series 1: Artist books
    See also Box 4
    - [An Argentinian Male Teenager.] Club de Orientacion Juvenil et infantil. Artist book. Wrappers. Staple bound. Stamped "Archive Copy." c1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Beau Geste Press. 1973-1974 catalogue with provision to keep adding sheets as you receive them. Mail order catalog of BGP publications with brief descriptions. Wrappers. 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chadwick, Helen and Mayor, David. Door to Door. Edition of 250. Artist book. Wrappers. Signed in black pen: "happy christmas father, love David X." 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Coum. Transmissions. Untitled postcard. Self-published. Stamped "Archive copy." 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. Pussywillow, a journal of conditions. Artist book. Wrappers. Stamped "Archive Copy." 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. Flechas. Artist book. Wrappers. Edition of 100. Feb. 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. A Testimonial of Hostage Objects. Printed by BGP for Fignal in Amsterdam, Holland. Artist book. Wrappers. Stamped Archive Copy. Edition of 300 copies. 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. Generacion. Libro I, Book I. Artist book. Wrappers. Dust jacket. Some hand correction. Stamped "Fun Fare Sites as Soon as Practicable." Edition of 200. 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. Generacion. Unfolded dust jacket. Rubber stamped "Fun Fare Sites as Soon as Practicable." 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. Libro Accion Libre/Beau Geste Press, England, Mexico. Distributed by Books Ltd., Leeds England. Mail order catalog of BGP publications available from first distributor. Wrappers. Staple bound. Feb./March 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. World Art Organizations. Organisation Mondiale de l'art. Organizacion Mundial del arte. Copy 43/60. Artist book. Wrappers. Staple bound. Signed and numbered. Dec. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ehrenberg, Matthias and Yael. Dibujos de Matthias y Yael. Published prior to adoption of name BGP. Artist book. Wrappers. Staple bound. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ehrenberg, Yael. Catch every Monday. Artist book. Wrappers. String bound. Edition of 59. Stamped "Archive copy." 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ehrenberg, Yael. Things by Yael. Artist book. Wrappers. Staple bound. Edition of 60. Stamped "Archive copy." 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Fisher, Allen. blueprint only. Spaces for Winter Solstice. Printed at BGP for Fluxshoe Exeter. Artist book. Wrappers. Staple bound. Stamped "Archive Copy." 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Fisher, Allen. taken the days after we had beef curry between 28.7.72 & 28.10.72. Artist book. Wrappers. Saddle-stitched. 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Freidman, Ken. The Aesthetics. Complete edition. First edition 91/300. March 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Gibbs, Michael. Lifeline. Published in edition of 100 by KONTEXTS. Artist book. Wrappers. Staple bound. Stamped "Archive copy." May 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Groh, Klaus. "Art Impressions"USA + Canada. Edition of 700 copies; 500 bound with Schmuck 7. BGP Barhatch Farm. Artist book. Wrappers. Staple bound. 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Haut, Woody. The Cartographers. Wrappers. Poems. Copy 107/400. 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hendrix, Jan. hoofsdstuk 1. Object book: loose cards in sewn-up paper potato sacks which are stitched closed. Unopened. #000026. Stamped "Archive Copy." 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hompson, Davi Det. Seven Postcards. Everyday Friendship Series. Self-published. 2 sets of postcards in the same wrapper. 13 postcards total. c 1972-3 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Koike, Ryp and Hiroko. Twelve Zodiac Signs. Artist book. Wrappers. Litho-offset drawings. Copy 4/150. 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Koslowski, Jaroslaw. Lesson. BGP, Barhatch Farm, Cranleigh, Surrey, England. Artist book. Wrappers. Edition of 900. 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Leggett, Michael. Afini/Erotica. Verse interpreted by Peter Foster-Marr. Edition of 200. Artist book. Wrappers. 1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Marroquin, Raul. How? Printed at Agora, Maastricht, Holland. Artist book. Wrappers. Staple bound. 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Maya, Pepe. Cuaderno de Apuntes. Portfolio containing 28 prints. Originals reproduced on paper plates and lithoed by F.Ehrenberg. 1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Mayor, David. autobook.(preface)(text). DIS/ -series. Artist book. Bound w/rubber band. 2nd edition of 200. Initialed., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Mayor, David. Extra. Some words and visions by david mayor. DIS/ -series. Artist book. Wrappers. Copy 89/100. 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Mayor, David. This is to Certify that I... Event cards, sheets. Wrappers. Plastic spine and enclosing sleeve. Tiny edition. 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - McCall, Anthony. Wipes Fades Dissolves. Artist book. Wrappers. Signed and numbered 18/20. Stamped "Archive Copy." 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - McCall, Anthony. Landscape for fire. Photograph by Carolee Schneemann, of event by Anthony McCall. Postcard. 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Musgrave, Victor. The First Lecture by the Intermediary. Printed by BGP, St. George's View. Artist book. Wrappers. Staple bound. Edition of 880. 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Nations, Opal L. Banners Death. Specially made by Opal L. Nations. Artist book. Wrappers. Staple bound. 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Naylor, Colin. The Book of the Sphinx. Printed by BGP, St. George's View. Artist book. Spiral bound. 42 identical pages. Edition of 450. 1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Plant, John. Save yourself for the hounds of Hell they can have you all to themselves. John Cale. Self-published card. Stamped "Archive copy." c1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Robertson, Clive and Su. Ehrenberg, Yael. Contact 26 of a year of.f. drawings. Deckle edged card. Stamped "Archive copy." 1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Saito, Takako. To my friends.Artist book in a solid hand-dyed box. Wrappers. Innumerable pages and several books within the book. Edition of 110.Signed. 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Tôt, Endre. Night Visit to the National Gallery. Artist book. Wrappers. Staple bound. Edition of 500. 1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Tsushiya, Yukio. Works in Progress 1972-73. Artist book. Wrappers. Staple bound. Initial mimeographic edition of 100. 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Vicuna, Cecilia. Sabor a mi. Bilingual edition in Spanish and English. Artist book. Wrappers. Edition of 250. Each book is different, containing envelopes rec'd by Vicuna, tree leaves,... 1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - W.O.R.K.S. w.o.r.k.s.c.o.r.e.p.o.r.t. Printed at BGP, St. George's View, Cullompton, Devon, UK. Artist book. Wrappers. Edition of 500: 300 for distribution by BGP, 200 by W.O.R.K.S. 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Vautier, Ben. Me Ben I Sign. Printed by BGP, Barhatch Farm. Artist book. Wrappers. Staple bound. Published as first chapeter of Ecrit pour la gloire a force de tourner en rond et d'etre jaloux.(1970) Edition of 950. 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Yoshida, Hideki. 1971.7.4. P.M. 2:00-4:00. Edition of 500. Artist book. Wrappers. Stapled. 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Erhenberg, Felipe. La Dolcena y el Pilon (Painter's Dozen). 12 lithographs in portfolio. Edition of 60. Each print hand-signed. 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. Cantata Dominical. The Sunday February 1972. Artist book. Wrappers. Signed and numbered. Copy 2/25. 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
    - Nations, Opal L., interpreted by Felipe Ehrenberg. The Man Who Entered Pictures. Artist book. Wrappers. Copy 96/150. June/July 1972, **Needs repair-spine (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
    - Nations, Opal L., interpreted by Felipe Ehrenberg. The Man Who Entered Pictures. Artist book. Wood covers. 30 copies bound into wood covers, signed by Nations and Ehrenberg. June/July 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 4)
    - Sitting Dog & Co. (Manifesto Pamphlet). 1972, Wrappers. Staple bound. 1st edition. (Oversize 3, Folder 5)
    - Sitting Dog & Co. (Manifesto Pamphlet.) 1972, Mimeographed envelope ready for mailing containing 5 cards. 2nd edition. (Oversize 3, Folder 6)
    - Artist unknown. In defence of memory. (Emancipation of a substitute) ,,Just a Free Zone Story - until this moment" Refill Time... Architecture. Balloon. Printed black on red rubber (a little dried out). n.d. (Othertype 4, Folder 1)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. -P-. Cardboard cigarette box hand-painted purple with a silver letter P containing 66 cards printed on 1 side w/letters A-Z and &. Stamped Archive Copy. Signed and numbered. 4/50. "a throw it yourself poetry kit." 1972 (Othertype 4, Folder 2)
    - Harding, Mary. 11 a.m. box. 5 cardboard boxes, nesting in one another, with original bromide prints printed by the artist. Initialed. Stamped Mary Harding Photo. Edition of 60. 1973 (Othertype 4, Folder 3)
    - Anon. (David Mayor). It's an Old Story. Artist book. Wrappers. Cloth-backed. Hand-stamped in 26 different colors. Limited ed. Tiny book 1 1/4" all round. 1974 (Othertype 4, Folder 4)
    - Mayor, David. Fragmen. Artist book. Wrappers. Staple bound. Signed. Very small edition. Poetry flip-book on card. c 1973 (Othertype 4, Folder 5)
    - Mayor, David. Microgames. (For want of title). Individually: Gong, Spiral, Frozen Phosphorus, Safety Ship Match Household. Matchbox containing card and 3 small matchboxes. Complete edition, Smaller matchboxes also sold separately. Edition of 40. 1973 (Othertype 4, Folder 6)
  - Series 2: Broadsides
    - Artist unknown. A Community of Duplicators, Printers and Artisans. - Our Press is Not a Business, It's a Way of Life. Flier. Mimeographed w/rubber stamps. Printed on both sides. Archive copy. c 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 7)
    - Artist unknown. Latest BGP Productions. Flier, offprint from Schmuck -Hungary (#3). 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 7)
    - Artist unknown. BGP, a communal company of duplicators disseminating, discovering, disconcerting & generally publishing... Mail order catalog of recently published titles. c1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 7)
    - Artist unknown. Mail order catalog of recently published titles. Stamped "Archive copy." c1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 7)
    - Artist unknown. The Man Who Entered Pictures. Flier announcing the publication. Stamped "Archive Copy." 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 8)
    - Artist unknown. The Man Who Entered Pictures. Flier announcing the publication. Tiny. 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 8)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. Title:/Run:/ISBN:/... Imposition sheet for book design. Stamped "Archive copy." c1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 9)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. Stencil need:/Printing to go:/Empty Page:/Stencil ready:/Printed. Imposition sheet for book design. Stamped "Archive copy." c1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 9)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. Schmuck America Latina. Flier to announce the Latin American Schmuck. Stamped "Archive copy." 2 copies. 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 9)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe/Wright, F. Terry. Invoice. BGP. BGP invoice form. Stamped "Archive copy." c 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 9)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe/Mayor, David. Joint Communique. BGP England/Libro Accion Libre/Mexico. Flier to announce the decentralization of BGP and the formation of BAAA, the Beau and Aloes Arc Association. 1974 (Oversize 3, Folder 10)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe/Gibbs, Michael. 19 Bowl Along to the Cumin-out even of Gingersnaps. Flier to announce evening events to launch Gingersnaps at Exeter Univ. Stamped "Archive copy." 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 10)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. Your Silence can destroy the heart of London. Speak Up! Kill the Piccadilly Plan. Flier to protest the redev't plan for Piccadilly, London. Stamped "Archive copy." c1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 10)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. The Fluxshoe. Travelling thru the U.K. from Oct. 72 to Oct. 73. Flier announcing the Fluxshoe to prospective venues. Stamped "Archive copy." 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 10)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. Surely this piece is by the famous artist Christo? Hey you country without a name: 14 Sept. 1973. Flier on Chile and Cambodia. Stamped "Archive copy." 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 10)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. Allende Vive is Alive. Flier. Stamped "Archive copy." 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 10)
    - Equipo Movimiento. Targetapostal. Post Card. Marroquin/Young-Tchong. Postcard. Stamped "Archive copy." 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 11)
    - Equipo Movimiento. A Reconstruction of Rodin's 'The Thinker." Jan van Eyck Academie, Maastricht, Holland. Flier to announce the availability of a performance piece to possible sponsors. Pola-photo by F. Ehrenberg and R. Marroquin. Stamped "Archive copy." 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 11)
    - Marroquin, Raul. Schuman, Marjo. Verhoeven, Anton, eds. Vandangos. News-sheet published by Agora (Maastrict), Dander (Maastrict); Jan v.Eyck Academy. Mentions BGP's UK distribution of Vandangos. 1974 (Oversize 3, Folder 11)
    - Mayor, David. curRent TiTlEs from BGP and Ass... Flier to announce publications (Oversize 3, Folder 12)
    - Compiled by David Mayor. Action on Behalf of Milan Knizak. Newsletter. "Please help!" written in blue at top of 1st page. 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 12)
    - Mayor, David. Schmuck BGP. Sheet to advertise advertising space in Schmuck Anthological. Stamped "Archive copy." 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 12)
    - Mayor, David. Christmas Events (for Mick Gibbs). Stamped "Archive copy." "Event scores." 1971 (Oversize 3, Folder 12)
    - Mayor, David. object: david mayor. Photo: tony joseph. Dis/-(flux) press. Single sheet, mimeographed from electronic stencil. "Archive copy." 1971 (Oversize 3, Folder 12)
    - Mayor, David. object: david mayor. Photo: tony joseph. Dis/-(flux) press. Single sheet, mimeographed from electronic stencil. "Archive copy." 1971 (Oversize 3, Folder 12)
    - Schneemann, Carolee. From the liberated cock book for women and others. Americana I Ching Apple Pie. Broadsheet. Hand-colored and tea-stained. Edition of 60. Signed. 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 13)
    - Schneeman, Carolee. From the Liberated Cock Book for Women and Others. Broadsheet. Mimeographed, hand-colored. Signed. Edition of 60. 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 13)
    - Artist unknown. "A Reading from Parts of a Body House Book. Carolee Schneeman. c 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 13)
    - Artist unknown. "Beau Geste Press announces the Publication of Parts of a Body House Book." Archive copy. c 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 13)
    - Artist unknown. BGP announces the publication of Parts of the Body House Book by Carolee Schneeman. Stamped "Archive copy." c 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 13)
    - Ward, Tony. BGP: Distributed by Other Books & So. BAAA. Flier to announce latest BGP and Arc Publications titles. c1976-77 (Oversize 3, Folder 14)
    - W.O.R.K.S. Immediate Gallery/W.O.R.K..S., Calgary, Canada. Flier to announce exhibition of BGP pubs. At the Immediate Gallery. Stamped "Archive copy." 1975 (Oversize 3, Folder 14)
    - Wright, F. Terry. BGP: A Community of Printers Duplicators & Craftsmen. Bookmark, visiting card. Stamped "Archive copy." 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 15)
    - Wright, F. Terry. The Cartographers. By Woody Haut. Flier to announce the publication. Letter press. Stamped "Archive copy." 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 15)
    - Wright, F. Terry. Quotation No. Quotation form for outside jobs produced by BGP. Stamped "Archive copy." 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 15)
  - Series 3: Serials
    - Dreck. Bits and pieces from the frontier. Artist publication. Wrappers. Staplebound, mimeographed, hand-painted cover. Jan. 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 16)
    - Fluxshoe Add End A 72-73 Edition of 550. 1974 (Oversize 3, Folder 17)
    - Schmuck (Schmuck Anthological No.1) Artist publication. Wrappers. Plastic spine. Many fold-outs. March 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 18)
    - French Schmuck (Schmuck Anthological No. 6) Tories object to "anarchist papers. Dossier Français. French Dosser. J.C. Lambert. Edition of 550. 1976 (Oversize 3, Folder 19)
    - Teutonic Schmuck (No. 7) Artist publication. Wrappers. Edition of 400. Dec. 1975 (Oversize 3, Folder 20)
    - Schmuck Iceland (Schmuck Anthological No. 4) Artist publication. Wrappers. Edition of 300. Hungarian Schmuck. 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 21)
    - Thomas Alva Edison Centenary Issue. Commemorating The Ices-72 Brain Drain Music Train. Special limited ed. No. 02/120. 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 22)
    - The Thomas Alva Edison Centenary Issue Commemorating the Ices-72 Brain Drain Music Train. Flier announcing the publication. Stamped "Good Grief!" and "Archive copy." 1972 (Oversize 3, Folder 22)
  - Series 4: Rubber stamps
    - Artist unknown (Carrion, Ulisses). Argument. Rubber stamp. n.d. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Artist unknown. Original Beau Geste Press rubber stamp. Bristol Rubber Stamp Manufacturing Co. n.d. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Artist unknown. Original Beau Geste Press rubber stamp. (Sun and 2 fish). Bristol Rubber Stamp Manufacturing Co. n.d. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Series 5: Flat files
    - BGP. Books and Anthologies of aRt by: 5-17 March 1976. Poster to announce exhibit of BGP publications at Galerie s:t Petri- Archive of Experimental and Marginal Art, Lund, Sweden. Edition of 500. 1976 (Othertype 5, Folder 1)
    - Humphrey is Here! being a broadsheet of thoughts gathered when BGP christened its M.A.N. two rev. letterpress cylinder. 1973 (Othertype 5, Folder 2)
- Accession 1999-081
  - Flyers n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Posters, flyer, Leandro Katz postcard, Pepe Maya letter and poster, Cecilia Vicuna letter and book maquette 1973 and n.d. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Felipe Ehrenberg's Pussywillow prototype, cover layout, text, flyer, etc., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence between David Mayor and Felipe Ehrenberg, 30 letters, 4 postcards, and 1 strip of gelatin silver prints. 1971-1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)